Guide to the Robert R. Wilson papers, 1936-2000.
Wilson, Robert R. papers, 1936-2000.
- Series II. Correspondence - General/Professional
  - Lyons, Jeremiah J., W. H. Freeman and Company, to R.R.W., Ithaca, re using article, "Particle Physics in the Cosmos," in collection of articles [pls], 11/17/1986 (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - Lyons, Louis M., Harvard University, to R.R.W., re dining with science writers covering AAAS conference [tls], 10/29/1946 (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - Mack, J. E., re which materials belong to which group [cc], 11/11/1942 (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - Mack., J. E., to Mr. E. E. Olsen, re nuts, bolts, screw, and washers [cc], 3/4/1943 (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - Mack, Julian, Santa Fe, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re 4" oil diffusion pumps [tls], 6/4/1946 (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - [Mack], Julian to "Dear Bobbo & Jane too," re winning Fermi Award [als]; clipping [phc], 12/1/1984 (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - Mackay, A. D., NYC from R.R.W., re price of Dysprosium Oxide [cc], 7/31/1941 (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - Mackay, A. D., NYC from R.R.W., re purchase of Dysprosium Oxide, draft [als], n.d. (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - Mackenzie, Ken, UCB, to R.R.W., Princeton University, re regulator tubes in high voltage supply [tls]; reply by John C. Turnbull, 11/30/1942 [cc], 11/19/1942 (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - Mackesey, T. W., C. U., from F. A. Long, C. U., re recent proposal for location of ring and research building for the 10 Gev synchrotron [phc], 1/9/1964 (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - Mackesey, T. W., C. U., from D. A. Edwards, C. U., re attached estimate of operating expenses for 10 Gev [cc], attachment [phc], 5/28/1964 (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - Mackesey, T. W., C. U., from R.R.W., re discussion with Architecture faculty and architects about 10 Gev design [cc], 4/21/1965 (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - Mackesey, T. W., C. U., from R.R.W., re help with getting 10 Gev design approved [cc], 6/22/1965 (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - Mackesey, T. W., C. U., to Paul Lattimore, Auburn, re 200 Gev in this area [cc], 8/27/1965 (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - Mackin, Robert J., Jr., ONR, to R.R.W., C. U., re visit to Ithaca [tls], 6/17/1955 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Mackin, Robert J., Jr., ONR, to R.R.W., C. U., re injector and thanks for tour of Ithaca facility [tls], 7/6/1955 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Mackinlay, Ian, Orinda, Ca., from R.R.W., re "light wells" in the synchrotron hall [cc], 2/4/1965 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - MacLeod, Clifton T., to Members of the Advisory Committee, Annual Rochester Conference on High Energy Nuclear Physics, re meeting to be held 1/31/1957 [mc], 1956 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - MacLeod, Clifton T., re P. S. list of 7 LNS staff to attend conference [cc, signed], n.d. (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Madison, John J., Arlington, Va., to R.R.W., re interview on subject of SSC and Human Genome Project [tls], abstract on study of research policy [pm]; note on recto, 8/12 [am], 6/25/1993 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Maglich, Bogdan C., Fusion Energy Corporation, to R.R.W., Columbia University, re approval of pre-proposal for the Energy Research Center (ERC) at King Abdulaziz University (KAU) [tls], 6/11/1981 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Magnuson, Warren G., United States Senate, to R.R.W., Manhattan Project, Santa Fe, re appreciation for recent testimony seeking to establish National Research Foundation [tls], 10/25/1945 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Malamud, Ernest, CERN, to R. R. W, C. U., re recent lab news and request for reference [tls], 9/26/1963 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Malamud, Ernest, Université de Lausanne, to R.R.W., C. U., re draft of paper on issues relative to physics exchange programs and contacts between the U. S. and the U.S.S.R. [pls]; reply, 3/15/1986 [phc], 1/7/1986 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Malamud, Ernest, Fermilab, to R.R.W., C. U., re discussion paper on the Illinois Science Center [tls], 7/24/1987 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Malina, Roger P., Leonardo, to R.R.W., Ithaca, re submitting an article [tls], note on recto [am], 12/29/1982 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Malott, Deane W., C. U., to R.R.W., C. U., re serving on committee on the Festival of Contemporary Arts [tls]; reply, 1/12/1954 [cc], 1/9/1954 (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - Malott, Deane W., C. U., to R.R.W., C. U., re accepting reappointment on committee on the Festival of Contemporary Arts [tls]; reply, 10/3/1955 [cc], 9/28/1955 (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - Malott, Deane W., C. U., to R.R.W., C. U., re congratulations on election to membership in The National Academy of Sciences [tls], 4/26/1957 (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - Malott, Deane W.: [Lloyd Elliott for Pres. Malott], C. U., to R.R.W., C. U., re invitation to a Russion scholar to spend a year at LNS [tls], 3/25/1958 (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - Manfred, Ernest F[red], NYC, to R.R.W., re request for autograph [als], 10/20/1945 (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - Manley, J[ohn] H., The University of Chicago, to R.R.W., Princeton University, re use of equipment [tls], 2/12/1943 (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - Manley, J[ohn] H., Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, to R.R.W., LNS, re neutron dosage measurement [tls]; reply, 5/19/1950 [cc], 4/24/1950 (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - Manley, J[ohn] H., Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, to R.R.W., LNS, re neutron dosimetry [tls]; reply, 8/10/1950 [cc], 7/7/1950 (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - Manley, J[ohn] H., University of Washington, Seattle, from R.R.W., LNS, re subject for summer course, travel plans [cc], 6/13/1951 (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - Manley, J[ohn] H., University of Washington, Seattle, from R.R.W., C. U., re search for additional instructors [tls], 3/16/1956 (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - Manley, J[ohn] H., Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, from R.R.W., C. U., re giving talk at Los Alamos [tls]; reply, 12/1/1959 [cc], 10/26/1959 (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - Mann, Alfred K., University of Pennsylvania, to R.R.W., C. U., re ThC" source [tls]; reply, 1/21/1957 [cc], 1/2/1957 (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - Mann, Alfred K., University of Pennsylvania, to R.R.W., C. U., re giving colloquium [tls], note on recto [am], 9/29/1959 (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - Mantsch, Paul, Fermilab, to R.R.W., C. U., re sculpture for area in front of the Industrial Center Building [tls], note on recto [ams], 10/17/1985 (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - Mantsch, Paul, Fermilab, to R.R.W., C. U., re sculpture in front of ICB [tls], 1/15/1986 (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - Mantsch, Paul, Fermilab, to R.R.W., C. U., re sculpture [tls], 8/15/1988 (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - Marcantonio, Vito, to R.R.W., C. U., re becoming member of Advisory Council of American Labor Party Executive Committee (telegram) [phc]; reply, 4/21/1948 (telegram) [phc], 4/20/1948 (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Marcham, John, C. U., to R.R.W., C. U., re speaking at University Council-Board of Trustees weekend program [tls], 9/8/1966 (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Marcolini, G., Ercole Marelli & C., to R.R.W., C. U., re "Synchrotron Progress Report" (NP-1246), working on plans for installation at University of Pisa [tls], 6/30/1953 (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Marcolini, G., Ercole Marelli & C., from William E. Wright, ONR, re electron synchrotron to be installed at University of Pisa [cc], 9/15/1953 (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Marcolini, G., Ercole Marelli & C., to R.R.W., C. U., re recent visit to Ithaca, request invitation for colleague to visit LNS [tls], 3/24/1954 (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Margulies, Michael, Management Associates, to William T. Golden, NYC, re science exhibit for new AAAS building [phc]; W. T. G. to M. M. 11/23/1992 [phc], 11/17/1992 (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Margulis, Stephen T., Bosti, to R.R.W., C. U., re recent visit [tls], 4/11/1983 (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Margulis, Stephen T., Bosti, to R.R.W., C. U., re discussion of design as inquiry [tls], attachment [phc], 4/11/1983 (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Marshak, Alfred, New York University, to R.R.W., C. U., re current projects, interest in returning to radiation biology and radioactive tracer studies on structure and function of cell nuclei in microorganisms and in higher plants and animals [als]; reply, 10/25/1948 [cc], 10/13/1948 (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Marshak, R. E., University of Rochester, from J. Gueron, Commissariat a L'Énergie Atomique, re exchange of research students [tls], notes to R.R.W. from R. E. M. [als], 8/2/1948 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R. E., University of Rochester, to R.R.W., re synchrotron betatron and bet (on who first produces mesons) [tls]; reply, 1/14/1949 [cc], 11/30/1948 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene], University of Rochester, to R.R.W., re method for getting at the neutron spectrum, health [als], 5/3/1949 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene], University of Rochester, to R.R.W., re one-day conference on High Energy Physics to be held at U. of R. on December 16, 1950 [mc, signed], 10/31/950 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene], University of Rochester, to R.R.W., re second Annual Conference on High Energy Physics [tls], 11/16/1951 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene], University of Rochester, to R.R.W., re R.R.W.'s projected book on High Energy Physics Techniques, hopes R.R.W. will take a look at his book on Meson Physics [tls], 1/25/1952 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene], University of Rochester, to R.R.W., C. U., re Third Annual Conference on High Energy Physics [tls], P. S. [als], 9/22/1952 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene], University of Rochester, from R.R.W., C. U., re preparing a tract on "Experimental Techniques in High Energy Accelerator Physics" [tls], P.S. [als], attachment "Interscience Tracts in Physics and Astronomy" [tm], list [cc], publishing terms [cc], 5/9/1953 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene], Université de Paris, to R.R.W., re work at Sorbonne, waiting for copies of papers [tls], 11/27/1953 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene], École Normale Superieure, to R.R.W., re visit to LNS by Dr. A. M. L. Messiah [als]; reply, 1/15/1954 [cc], 1/12/1954 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene], Université de Paris, from R.R.W., re thanks for preview of paper "The Pion," comments on analogy [cc], 9/27/1955 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene], University of Rochester, to R.R.W., C. U., re Seventh Annual Conference on High Energy Nuclear Physics [tls]; reply, 11/27/1956 [cc], 10/1/1956 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, Robert E., University of Rochester, from R.R.W., re tour for visiting international scientists [cc], 1/29/1957 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene], University of Rochester, to R.R.W., C. U., re 10th Annual International Conference on High Energy Physics [tls], 2/24/1960 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene], University of Rochester, to Dr. W. K. H. Panofsky, re brief account of discussions which took place during the Russian trip with regard to Soviet-American cooperation in high energy physics [cc], D. I. Blokhintsev to R. E. M., 1/14/1960, re Tenth Conference on High Energy Physics [thc], Eugene B. Skolnikoff, to R. E. M., 5/4/1960 [thc], 6/17/1960 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene], CERN, to R.R.W., C. U., re papers for Rochester Conference, life at CERN [tls], Brunislaw Buras to R. E. M., 9/21/1960, re publications produced at Rochester Conference [thermo-fax], R. E. M. to B. B., 9/30/1960 [cc], 10/3/1960 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene], University of Rochester, to R.R.W., C. U., re notes on Soviet theoretical effort in high energy physics [tls], notes [mc], 12/13/1960 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene], University of Rochester, to R.R.W., C. U., re request for status report on tract [tls], P. S. [al], list of tracts in preparation [phc, 1 p. cc]; reply, 2/28/1963 [cc], 12/27/1962 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene], University of Rochester, to R.R.W., C. U., re 10 Bev proposal [tls], 4/11/1963 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene], University of Rochester, from R.R.W., C. U., re making 10 Gev electron synchrotron available to physicists at other institutions, 5/13/1963 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene], to R.R.W., re recent letter [als]; Norman F. Ramsey, Harvard University, to R. E. M., 1/25/1963 [phc]; reply, 4/1/1963 [phc]; N. F. R. to Robert F. Bacher, C. I. T.,1/15/1963 [thc], 5/15/1963 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene], University of Rochester, to R.R.W., C. U., re brief report on tract [tls], P. S. [al], list of Interscience Tracts on Physics and Astronomy [phc], 1/1/1964 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene], University of Rochester, from R.R.W., C. U., re volume of contributed writings for Hans A. Bethe's 60th birthday celebration [tls]; reply, 6/1/1965 [cc], 5/13/1965 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshak, R[obert] E[ugene]: Luke W. Mo, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University to William L. Woodard, nominating Dr. Robert Eugene Marshak for the Enrico Fermi Prize for 1987 [tls], personal data and curriculum vita of R. E. M. [phc], 2/18/1987 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Marshall, Lauriston C., Southwest Center for Advanced Studies, to R.R.W., C. U., re visit to LNS, sending some publications, invitation to Dallas [tls], 9/30/1965 (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - Martelli, Giuseppe, Istituto di Fisica dell' Universita di Pisa, from R.R.W., re recent visit, names of Japanese using cloud chamber [cc], 12/2/1953 (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - Martin, Marvin, UCB, from R.R.W., re glue used on donut parts, lab news [cc], 11/8/1948 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Martin, Paul, to "POPA Task Group I," re APS and Large Physics Facilities [phc], note on recto [als], 12/13/1984 (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - Martyl to R.R.W.: clipping [phc], 1995 (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - Marwedel, Ted, C. W. Marwedel, to R.R.W., Princeton University, re hard solder called phospher copper [tls], 1/6/1942 (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - Maschke, Al: John Peoples, Fermilab, to R.R.W., Ithaca, re death of A. M. [tls]; Bob Daniels to J. P., 3/27/1995, re death of A. M. and possible memorial [phc]; R.R.W. to J. P., 1/11/1995 [pl], 3/28/1995 (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - Maschke, Al: R.R.W., Ithaca, to Dr. Lyle W. Smith, BNL, re memorial article about A. M. at Fermilab [pl], 4/28/1995 (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - Maschke, Millie, Las Cruces, NM, from R.R.W., Ithaca, re Al's death [pl], corrections on recto [am]; reply, 5/11/1995 [pls], 4/3/1995 (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - Mastick, Donald F., AEC, to R.R.W., C. U., re second volume of Annual Reviews of Nuclear Science [tls]; reply 9/5/1951 [cc], 7/27/1951 (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Mastick, Donald F., AEC, to R.R.W., C. U., re second volume of Annual Reviews of Nuclear Science [tls]; reply 10/4/1951 [cc], 9/21/1951 (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Matheson, James C., URA, to R.R.W., C. U., re SSC: 4 letters from and to Alvin W. Trivelpiece, AEC, and Memorandum of Understanding entered into by seven principal participating US institutions in high energy physics, endorsed by Board of Trustees on 12/9/1983 [tls], 4 letters/memos [phc], Memorandum of Understanding [phc], 6/18/1985 (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Matheson, Martin, John Wiley & Sons, Inc., to R.R.W., Manhattan District Project, Los Alamos, re possible book on experimental nuclear physics [tls], 1/4/1945 (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Matheson, Martin, John Wiley & Sons, Inc., to R.R.W., Manhattan District Project, Los Alamos, re possible book on experimental nuclear physics [tls], 1/9/1945 (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Mathews, Bob O., ONR, to R.R.W., C. U., re UNIVAC use opportunity [addressed ml], note on recto [als], 4/27/1953 (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Matreer, Victor, season's greetings [card], 12/n.y. (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Mattice, M. C., C. U., to Dean L. S. Cottrell, Jr., R.R.W., R. C. Knox, H. E. Weatherlow, G. S. Frank, P. J. Krebs, G. F. Rogalsky, H. L. Williams, C. R. Wilson, J. A. Peters, J. H. Johnson, R. W. Seidel, re floor plans for LNS [cc], floor plans [photo-offset copies], 1/20/1949 (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Mattmueller, Anne, Naperville, Ill., to R.R.W., re her husband Fred [als], note on recto, 3/28/1994 [am], 3/28/1994 (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Matyas, Robert M., to Don Swayze, X-Cel Finishing Corporation, re orders for cementing fishpaper to C-sections, fabricating 1-inch C-section stacks, and for fabrication of wedges [cc], 6/1/1953 (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Matyas, Robert M., C. U., to R.R.W., C. U., re equipment storage [tls], 3/25/1954 (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Mazar, B., Hebrew University, to R.R.W., C. U., re thanks for cyclotron shipped to Dr. S. Cohen [tls]; reply, 12/31/1956 [cc], 11/22/1956 (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - McArtor, Vernon W., AEC, to R.R.W., C. U., re reappointment to Historical Advisory Committee [tls], attachment [printed form with cc entries], 12/17/1963 (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - McArtor, Vernon W., AEC, to R.R.W., C. U., re reappointment to Historical Advisory Committee [tls], attachment [printed form with cc entries], 12/11/1964 (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - McComas, James D., Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University to R.R.W., Ithaca, re creating video tape of reminiscences of human side of the massive American programs of nuclear research and development following World War II [tls]; reply, 4/17/1991 [pl], 4/10/1991 (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - McConnell, R. A., University of Pittsburgh, to Professor T. H. Osgood, American Journal of Physics, re extrasensory perception [mc], 1/16/1953 (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - McCoy, David W., World Republic, to R.R.W., re struggle for peace [tls], 1/2/1948 (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - McDaniel, "Mac" [Boyce D.], to R.R.W., re traveling to Middletown, Ohio to see about getting some flux bar steel for synchrotron [cc], Sunday Eve, 10 P.M. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - McDaniel, B[oyce] D., to Professor Paolo Budini, Istituto Nazionale di Fisica Nucleare, re letter to Professor Wilson about Dr. Filosofo visiting LNS, R.R.W. away but colleagues could show him around or he could contact R.R.W. in California [cc], 9/15/1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - McDaniel, B[oyce] D., to Robert Eisberg, University of Minnesota re letter to R.R.W., 8/19/1958, re borrowing 6" G. E. hydrogen bubble chamber [cc]; R. E. to R.R.W., 8/19/1958 [tls]; B. D. M. to R.R.W., 9/11/1958 re visit to California and loan of bubble chamber [cc]; Robert B. Meigs, C. U., to Roger Knox, C. U., re bubble chamber [tls]; H. Hurwitz, Jr., G. E. to R.R.W., re bubble chamber donation [tls], 10/21/1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - McDaniel, B[oyce] D., files: John W. DeWire, Cornell Radiological Safety Committee, to Robert W. Kirkman, AEC, re incident in laboratory resulting in exposure of laboratory personnel, text of night letter [cc]; J. W. D. to R. W. K., re laboratory incident, detailed report [cc], table of radiation level data, 10/15/1958 [cc]; Peter C. Stein, LNS, to B. D. M., re exposure to radiation [cc]; report by B. D. M. on P. C. S.'s exposure and steps taken, 10/28/1958 [tms]; report on radioactive source by Roger Knox, 10/28/1958 [tms], 10/13/1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - McDaniel, Boyce D., LNS, to Dr. William E. Wright, ONR, re renewal of ONR contract [mc], proposal [mc]; report of work 1/1/1957-12/31-1958 [mc], 12/15/1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - McDaniel, B[oyce] D., files: F. E. Mineka, C. U., to "Chairmen of Departments," re projected enrollment [cc]; reply, 2/4/2959 [cc, signed], 1/16/1959 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - McDaniel, B[oyce] D., files: Arthur H. Peterson, C. U., to B. D. M., LNS, re University funds not be used for flowers for ill persons or funerals [tls], 1/19/1959 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - McDaniel, Boyce D., Comitato Nazionale Per Le Ricerche Nucleari, Frascati, to R.R.W., re lab news, comments on LNS [tls], 9/1959 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - McDaniel, Boyce D., Comitato Nazionale Per Le Ricerche Nucleari, Frascati, to R.R.W., C. U., re electron scattering experiment information, lab news [als], 11/17/1959 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - McDaniel, Boyce D., to R.R.W., C. U., re design of machine to allow future changes, lab news from Frascati [als]; reply, 4/7/1960 [cc]; B. D. M. to R.R.W., 4/21/1960, 11/29/1959 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - McDaniel, Boyce D., LNS, to R.R.W., NYC, re recent visit and invitation to return to Ithaca [tls]; reply, draft, n.d. [al], 1/30/1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - McDaniel, Boyce D.: "Nomination for National Medal for Science" form [phc], [1987] (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - McDaniel, Boyce D.: R. W. W. to Dr. William L. Woodward, U. S. Department of Energy, re seconding nomination of B. D. M. for Enrico Fermi Award, draft [phc], Karl Strauch, Harvard University to W. L. W., re nomination of B. D. M. for Fermi Award [phc], B. D. M. vita [phc], 3/26/1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - McDaniel, Boyce D.: R. W. W. to Mrs. Nona Shepard, U. S. Department of Energy, re nomination of B. D. M. for Fermi Award [pl]; reply, 9/23/1994 [tls], 9/2/1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - McDaniel, Paul W., AEC, to "Sherwood Steering Committee," re meeting in Los Alamos, October 12-14, 1959 [cc], 8/10/1959 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - McDaniel, Paul W., AEC, from R.R.W., re resignation from Sherwood Project [cc]; reply, 10/14/1959 [tls], 9/15/1959 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - McDaniel, Paul W., AEC, to R.R.W., C. U., re meeting arrangements (telegram) [phc], 9/25/1959 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - McDaniel, Paul W., AEC, from R.R.W., re serving on a scientific selection committee to consider proposals for two facilities interested in implementing electron-positron storage rings [tls]; reply, 4/30/1954 [cc], 4/30/1960 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - McDaniel, Paul W., AEC, from H. Stanley Livingston, M. I. T., re Storage Ring Review Committee and modification of proposal [phc], 6/24/1964 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - McDaniel, Paul W., AEC, to R.R.W., C. U., re report of Storage Ring Committee, sincere thanks for serving [tls]; P. W. M., to H. Stanley Livingston, M. I. T., re Storage Ring Review Committee Report [thc], 8/6/1964 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - McDaniel, Paul W., AEC, to R.R.W., C. U., re reopening the question of electron-positron storage ring devices, pleads for help in reviewing CEA material and SLAC results [tls]; reply, 7/30/1965 [cc], 6/14/1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - McDaniel, Paul W., AEC, to R.R.W., C. U., re thanks for comments [tls], P. W. M., to M. Stanley Livingston, Harvard University, re comments by reviewers [phc], 8/26/1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - McDaniel, Paul W., AEC, to R.R.W., C. U., re policy outlined in document "Policy for National Action in the Field of High Energy Physics" [tls], 12/28/1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - McDaniel, Paul W., AEC, to R.R.W., C. U., re meeting on high energy physics policy considerations [tls], agenda [cc], list of participants [cc], 1/13/1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - McDonald, Ralph, National Committee on Atomic Information (NCAI), to R.R.W., Harvard University, re first meeting of NCAI [tls]; reply, 11/26/1946 [cc], 11/15/1946 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - McDonald, Ralph, NCAI, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re invitation to first annual meeting of the member organizations [tls], 12/13/1946 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - McDonald, Ralph, NCAI, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re selection of a Nominating Committee [tls], 12/13/1946 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - McGinniss, Joe, Bennington College, to R.R.W., re visit to Ithaca to interview R.R.W. and Jane for book he is writing on life at Los Alamos during and immediately after World War II [tls], 3/6/1984 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - McHenry, Dean E., University of California, Santa Cruz, to R.R.W., Ithaca, re new campus [tls]; reply, 2/3/1964 [cc], 1/8/1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - McIntyre, Peter M., Houston Advanced Research Center (HARC), to R.R.W., Ithaca, re proposal for development of a 13 Tesla dual dipole for future hadron colliders [tls], note on recto [am], 10/20/1993 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - McKenzie, Kenneth, University of British Columbia, from R.R.W., re model oscillator [cc], 1/23/1947 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - McKinney, R. L., AEC, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re expired subcontract No. 67 (Prime Contract W-35-058-Eng-71 -- Terminated) [tls, cc], 3/15/1948 (Box 3, Folder 4)